### Summary

Software Engineer with great experience in creating usable and maintainable software for a wide range of businesses, including Augmented Reality and Financial Services. Strong technical background with a Master's Degree in Computer Engineering from the University of Florida. Experience in both large corporations and startups in the US and the Netherlands. Also, have taught C programming to students in a coding bootcamp in Colombia for half a year. Since 2020, I have done some contract work remotely as a digital nomad, but I am now looking for a challenging, onsite, full-time role, preferably in Amsterdam or New York. Most importantly, I am seeking a fun team to work with. (Nationality: Dutch)

## Recent Work Experience

# Tradomate BV (Financial Services)

Amsterdam, Netherlands / Remote August 2021 - January 2023

founder

- Idea was to make an algorithmic trading platform for dummies
- Built two engines in C++, one for parsing natural language queries and one for interpreting strategies in a custom DSL
- Built a flask backend and deployed to GCP with Docker Compose and Github Actions, the C++ code is run with pybind11
- Designed a frontend in Figma and hired a developer to build the frontend with Next.js
- Successfully deployed the natural language stock query platform at stockselect.ai
- Made a pitch deck and tried to raise capital from multiple angel investors without success

# SC IT Services (IT Consulting Services)

Amsterdam, Netherlands / Remote February 2020 - November 2022

Sole Proprietor and Remote Contractor

- \* Burst, a crypto startup based in New York (Jan 22 Nov 22)
  - First engineering hire
  - Built the Burst iOS App in Swift with CI/CD pipelines
  - Built the Backend in Node.js, integrated with PrimeTrust, deployed on AWS
  - Helped in the hiring of engineers to grow the team
  - Helped with the AWS Deployment Setup / Architecture
- \* Daily.js, a video calling startup based in San Francisco (Aug 21 Dec 21)
  - Compile the Rust WebRTC Platform codebase for iOS
  - WebRTC Video Calling Demo for iOS
  - iOS CI/CD pipelines
  - Build the first version of iOS Native SDK
- \* Athos, a training garment startup based in Silicon Valley (Feb 20 Apr 21)
  - Build C++ signal processing algorithms for live EMG and ECG Data
  - Integrated new C++ signal processing algorithms into the iOS mobile app
  - Redesign fully the native app UI with neumorphic designs using Swift and UIKit
  - Create iOS CI/CD pipelines with fastlane and jenkins
  - Interview new candidates
  - Write embedded firmware and also the corresponding iOS platform code that communicates with the firmware over BLE 5.0 using Zephyr RTOS and CoreBluetooth

# Moneyou / ABN AMRO (Mobile Banking)

Senior iOS Engineer - Contract

Amsterdam, The Netherlands / Onsite March 2018 - December 2018

- Helped build the MoneyouGo app in Swift using UIKit and RxSwift

- Helped design a reactive VIPER based system architecture for iOS
- Interview new iOS Candidates
- Won the moneyou hackathon and successfully implemented suggested features in the banking app
- Helped build AWS lambdas for banking services using Node.js serverless technologies

## Markplaats / Ebay Inc. (Mobile Classifieds)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands / Onsite

Senior iOS Engineer - Full Time

June 2016 - December 2017

- Only developer for the 2dehands.be App for Belgium with millions of users.
- Part of the EBay global mobile team building classified apps for 11 different countries
- Setup all required processes such as Automated Testing, Continuous Integration, Crash Analysis etc.
- Won the markplaats company hackathon
- Successfully hired and trained replacement for the role before exit

## Some Previous Work Experience

### Layar / Blippar (Augmented Reality)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands / Onsite

Senior Software Engineer - Full Time

November 2014 - May 2016

- Only Developer for the iOS Layar App that makes millions of users see Augmented Reality
- Only Developer for the iOS Layar SDK that help businesses make Augmented Reality solutions
- Part of the team building the Blippar App for visual search
- Contributed to several C++ cross platform projects with Kalman Filters, Computer Vision etc

## IceMobile Agency (Digital Agency)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands / Onsite

Senior iOS Engineer - Full Time

February 2014 - November 2014

- Senior developer in the iOS development team working on Jumbo app project

#### Ebuddy (Chat)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands / Onsite

iOS Developer - Full Time

June 2013 - January 2014

- Developer in the iOS development team for XMS app with more than 1m users

### MicroStrategy Inc. (Business Intelligence)

McLean, VA, USA / Onsite

Software Engineer - Full Time

September 2010 - January 2012

- Developer in iOS team building the Microstrategy Mobile SDK

#### Citisync (Event Management)

Gainesville, FL, USA / Onsite

iOS Developer - Contract

January 2010 - July 2010

- Singlehandedly built the citisync iOS Application. This was when iOS 3 was the latest version. Also my first experience as an iOS Developer and it piqued my interest in the field

## Bloomberg LP (Financial Services)

New York, NY, USA / Onsite

Financial Software Development Intern - Full Time

May 2009 - August 2009

- As an intern in the manhattan office, I helped out with a number of projects in the Global Trading team writing code in C++ and managing large mainframe supercomputers

## Education

## University of Florida

Gainesville, FL, USA August 2008 - August 2010

Masters in Computer Engineering

- CGPA: 3.6/4.0

## Volunteering Experience

### Holberton School (Education)

Colombia / Onsite

Resident Software Engineer - Full Time

September 2019 - December 2019

- As the resident software engineer in Cali and Barranquilla I was responsible for overseeing the technical education of the first batch of 50 students in both branches
- Taught students not just C programming but also behavioural and professional skills.
- Students were able to implement their own POSIX compliant shell in C and both ended up being one of the top performing cohorts at Holberton School.